<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-24T16:13:09-05:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alex Lu</title><subtitle>Alex's personal blogging site</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Python Quiz</title><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2022/08/23/alex-quiz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python Quiz" /><published>2022-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2022/08/23/alex-quiz</id><author><name>Alex Lu</name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you a 1337 coder?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alex Lu Resume</title><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/2022/08/23/Alex-Lu-Resume.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alex Lu Resume" /><published>2022-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/2022/08/23/-Alex-Lu-Resume</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yixuan Lu Aspiring programmer, Del Norte Sophomore GPA: Unweighted:4.0/Weighted:4.28 San Diego, CA 92127 (858) 413-4998 maodou1258@gmail.com LEADERSHIP CyberAegis Team, Organization Lead and Linux Specialist JULY 2021-PRESENT Del Norte’s CyberPatriot Team Nationwide competition for cyber-security and real-time cyber threats. 4 years of experience, 2 years of leadership. Design Training materials for team practice. Presentation and lessons on Linux concepts Organization of club meetings and lessons Construct training images (virtual machines) for team members to practice competition skills Proctoring club tryouts and other events. Project Art of Learning, VP of Project Operations MAY 2022-PRESENT A 501(c)(3) non-profit organization aimed to provide one-to-one tutoring sessions in math and computer science for low-income, immigrant, and refugee students. Maintain social media platform Organize Club Events Assist club directors with curriculum and activities. Del Norte Physics Tutoring Club, Secretary SEPT 2021-PRESENT School club designed to assist high school students in physics 1-2, AP Physics C: Mechanics, and AP Physics C: Electricity &amp; Magnetism. Keeps record of club activities. Maintaining club face and advertisement. EXPERIENCE Internship, Franklin Research Internship Program MAY 2021 - JULY 2021 Research Program dedicated to various research topics under a mentor. Developed statistics and data collection skills Researched the efficacy of various recommendation algorithms. Studied the basic topics of machine learning. Regression Classification Volunteer, Education for Nepal, Math tutor OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT Cooperated with students from Nepal Taught students valuable skills in the field of mathematics Covered a broad range of topics including Algebra, trigonometry, and pre-calculus concepts Created tutoring videos for students Volunteer, Cyber Education Initiative, Tutor JULY 2020 - SEPT 2020 Club’s purpose was to inform young children about the importance of safety in the cyberspace and how to protect oneself from cyberattacks Topics taught: Basics of the Linux OS and terminal. Security countermeasures on the windows OS Computer Networking and how network devices communicate Volunteer, 3D-printing club NOVEMBER 2020 - JANUARY 2021 Club’s purpose is to utilize 3D printing technology, to produce safe and usable shields for medical workers during Covid-19. Created around 40 masks SKILLSET Programming Experience: 2-3 years of experience in Python. Currently studying C/C++ language, algorithms, and data structures. Cybersecurity principles: Experience in white-hat hacking, red vs blue scenarios, familiarity with Linux and windows forensics tools. Linux Environment: Familiar with navigating the terminal and the Linux file system. Git: Aware of the basic functions of the software control tool for group collaboration. Computer Networking: Basic knowledge of networking devices, OSI model, and experience with Cisco packet tracer. Planning for CCNA examination. Computer Architecture: Started learning the x86 and ARM architectures. Mathematics: Familiar with Trigonometry, Algebra, and Calculus concepts. AWARDS CyberPatriot 2nd Place nationally Middle School division (12th season) 8th Place nationally High School (Open) Division (13th season) 4th Place nationally High School (Open) Division (14th season) Socal CyberCup 1st Place Junior Varsity Division (2019-2020) California Cyber Innovation Challenge 9th Place High School Difficult Division, led the team as Team Captain President’s Volunteer Service Award Gold Award - Teens, 100+ hours of volunteer work]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Jupyter Notebook</title><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2022/08/20/example-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Jupyter Notebook" /><published>2022-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2022/08/20/example-post</id><author><name>Alex Lu</name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first Jupyter notebook on my blog!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/markdown/2022/08/19/hello-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2022-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/markdown/2022/08/19/hello-world</id><author><name>Alex Lu</name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first blog post, hobbies + some code!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fastpages Notebook Blog Post</title><link href="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2020/02/20/test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fastpages Notebook Blog Post" /><published>2020-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/jupyter/2020/02/20/test</id><author><name></name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tutorial of fastpages for Jupyter notebooks.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/images/chart-preview.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://ylu-1258.github.io/YLu-Blog/images/chart-preview.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>